http://www.esf.edu/privacy/

Ranger School
Gateways for...
Partners
Students:
Accepted
New (orientation, first weeks)
Library
Programs:
Bookstore / ESF Merchandise
Bursar | Business Office Events Calendar Financial Aid & Scholarships Human Resources & Jobs News Site Index Sustainability @ ESF Visit
Directions, Maps,
Lodging
SEARCH
& INDEX
People Search (Faculty, Staff, Grad Students)
The ESF Employee Directory
was moved to improve information security for campus contact information. You can now reach the directory through your Faculty/Staff or MyESF student portal.
Faculty & Staff Login MyESF Login
Advanced Directory
Search ESF
A to Z:   A-B  |  C  |  D-E  |  F-G-H  |  I-J-K-L  |  M-N-O  |  P  |  Q-R  |  S  |   T-U-V-W
About ESF Academic Calendar Academic Governance Academic Programs
Undergraduate | Graduate
Adirondack Ecological Center (AEC) Adirondack Interpretive Center (AIC) Administration, Vice President for Administrative Updates; Policies & Procedures
Admission
Undergraduate | Graduate
Alumni Alumni Events Alumni, Parents & Friends Gateway American Chestnut Research and Restoration Project American Fisheries Society American Society for Photogrammetry & Remote Sensing American Water Resources Association Analytical and Technical Service
Animal Care Annual Reports (ESF) Appointment Forms Athletics Benefits Information (SUNY) Biotechnology in Forestry Center Board of Trustees Bookstore Branding and Style
Guide (logos, seals, templates) Business Affairs Bursar
Calendar of Alumni Events Calendar of Campus Events Campus Tour Campuses (Syracuse, Adirondacks, etc.) Career Services Career & Job Web Resources Catalog (program requirements, policies, courses) CCDR—Center for Community Design Research
CCLP—Center for Cultural Landscape Preservation
Center for Native Peoples and the Environment Center for the Urban Environment (CUE) Centers & Institutes (Research) Change of Major form (PDF) Chemistry, Department of Chestnut Project Clubs and Orgs (Student) College Foundation (ESF) Committee on Curriciculum Communications, Office of
Computing Informaton and Log-ins Computing and Network Services Conferences (ESF Open Academy) Continuing Education Council for Community Design Research Council for Geospatial Modeling and Analysis Cranberry Lake Biological Field Station Counseling Services Current Students Gateway
Departments, Academic Development, Office of Directions to ESF Directory of People and Offices Diversity and Inclusion Earth Week E-Center: Environmental Resources from SUNY-ESF Educational Outreach Electron Microscope Laboratory
Empire State Paper Research Institute Employee Assistance Program (EAP) Employee Benefits Information (SUNY) Employers & Partners Gateway Employers: Post Job & Internship Listings Employment Opportunities Environmental Decision Making, Graduate Certificate in Environmental and Forest Biology, Department of Environmental Health and Safety
Environmental Information Series Environmental Resources Engineering, Department of Environmental Science, Division of Environmental Studies, Department of ESF Facts ESF in the High School (Outreach) ESF Merchandise Events on Campus Experiential Learning & Outreach, Office of Extension
Facilities, Labs & Services
Faculty & Staff Gateway
Families & Friends Gateway
Feinstone Awards
Financial Aid and Scholarships
First-Year Student Admissions
First Year Students (New Student website)
Forest & Natural Resources Management
Forest Properties
Freshman (First-Year) Admissions
Geospatial Modeling and Analysis (Council for) Giving to ESF GPES (Graduate Program in Environmental Science) Graduate School
Graduate Admission Visit ESF
Graduate Student Association Graduation Great Lakes Research Consortium (GLRC) Greenhouses
Health Care & Insurance (for students) Heiberg
Forest
High School Students: Application and Admission Honors Program Housing Human Resources, Office of (HR) Huntington Wildlife Forest Hydrologic System Science
Inclusion, Diversity & Equity Institutes & Centers, Research Institutional Biosafety Committee (IBC) Instructional Technology Service (classroom media) International Students Internships
James F. Dubuar Memorial Forest
Jobs
Employment at ESF (ESF Human Resources) Listings for ESF Alumni/Students (ESF Career Services)
Post a Job or Internship Resources (links to many sites)
K-12
programs The Knothole (student publication)
Labs, Facilities & Services Lafayette Road Experiment Station
Landscape Architecture, Department of Law: Pre-law at ESF
Libraries Lifelong Learners
Media Technology (ITS) Michael M. Szwarc Polymer Research Institute Moon Library Native Peoples and the Environment, Center for N.C. Brown Center for Ultrastructure Studies Newcomb Campus News
New Graduate Students New Undergraduate Students New York Great Lakes Research Consortium NFI (Northern Forest Institute, Newcomb Campus)
Non-matriculated Students Northern Forest Institute (NFI, Newcomb Campus)
NYS DEC Environmental Education Camp
NY State Employee Assistance Program OELO (Office of Experiential Learning & Outreach) Open Academy Organizational Charts Orientation Outreach (Educational)
Pack Demonstration Forest
Pack Environmental Institute Pack Experimental Forest
Paper and Bioprocess Engineering, Department of Parent's Page Patuxent Wildlife Research Center
(USDI/USGS) Payroll
People & Offices
Physical Plant Planned Giving Police
(University Police) Policies & Procedures; Administrative Updates Polymer Research Institute
Pre-Professional Advising
Pre-Health Pre-Law Pre-Public Administration
President Privacy Policy Provost Purchasing
Quality of Work Life Committee QUEST- Quantifying Uncertainty in Ecosystem Studies
Radiation Safety Committee
Radiation Safety Manual (Word)
Randolph G. Pack Environmental Institute
Ranger School Re-admission to ESF (and withdrawl) Regional Campuses
Registrar Research
Research Foundation Employment and Forms Research, Institutes & Centers Research Programs, Office of (ORP) Roosevelt Wild Life Station
Safety/Security Committee Science and Engineering Fair (K-12 Outreach) Scientific Diving Program Service Social Media sites Sponsored Programs Spotlight on Student Research & Outreach Staff & Faculty Gateway Student Affairs, Office of the Dean Student
Employee Information
Student Employment Student Events Calendar Student Gateway (current students) Student Handbooks Student Health Care & Insurance Student Involvement & Leadership (activities, clubs/orgs) Student Organizations and Clubs Student Research Positions Student Support Study Abroad
Style Guide (logos, seal, templates)
Success - Student, Faculty and Alumni stories
Summer Semester
SUNY Homepage
SUNY Benefits Information
Sustainability, Office of
Sustainability Management, BS Online Program
Syracuse Pulp and Paper Foundation
Thousand Islands Biological Station
Tour the Campus Top 10 New Species Trailhead Café Transfer Student Admissions Transfer Students, New (fist weeks, orientation)
Tropical Timber Information Center Trustees, Board of Tutoring
Undergraduate Admissions Undergraduate Student Association (USA)
University Police Urban Environmental Science, About Urban Programs at ESF USDA Forest Service Urban Forest Research Unit Vice President for Administration Video/Multimedia Production (ITS) Visit ESF Visiting Students (non-matriculated, continuing ed.) Voter Registration Web at ESF Wildflower Restoration Project
Willow Biomass for Bioenergy Project Withdrawal from ESF (and re-admission) Wood Products Engineering Laboratory Wood Utilization Service Woodsmen Team Women's Caucus Work-Study Employment Information Writing, Rhetoric and Commumications Program Writing Resource Center
SOCIAL
LOG IN
APPLY
GIVE
Administration
SUNY-ESF Privacy Policy
Printable version (PDF)
The State University of New York College of Environmental Science and Forestry Internet Privacy Policy ESF.edu's Commitment to Privacy The State University of New York College of Environmental Science and Forestry (ESF), is committed to protecting your privacy and making it easier and more efficient for individuals and businesses to interact with ESF. We recognize it is critical for individuals and businesses to be confident that their privacy is protected when they visit esf.edu. You can travel through most of esf.edu without giving us any information about yourself. Sometimes we do need information to provide services you request, and this commitment of privacy explains our online information practices. This policy describes what information is collected and how that information is used. Because this privacy policy only applies to this website, you should examine the privacy policy of any website that you might access using this website. ESF collects personal information about you that you provide voluntarily by sending an email, completing the ESF Information Request Form, or completing the online application. ESF may use online phone directories and other internet search services to collect and update information used for college business and services. This policy is consistent with the provisions of the Internet Privacy and Security Act, the Freedom of Information Law, and the Personal Privacy Protection Law. Information Collected Automatically When You Visit esf.edu When visiting esf.edu, ESF automatically collects and stores the following information about your visit:
The Internet Protocol address of the computer that accessed our website The type of browser, its version and the operating system on which that browser is running The webpage from which the user accessed the current webpage The date and time of the user's request The pages that were visited and the amount of time spent at each page
None of the above-mentioned information is deemed to constitute personal information by the Internet Privacy and Security Act. The information that is collected automatically is used to improve esf.edu's content and to help ESF understand how users are interacting with its website. This information is collected for statistical analysis and to determine what information is of most and least interest to our users. The information is not collected for commercial marketing purposes and ESF is not authorized to sell or otherwise disclose the information collected from esf.edu for commercial marketing purposes. Information Collected When You Email esf.edu or Complete a Transaction During your visit to esf.edu you may send an email to ESF. Your email address and the contents of your message will be collected. The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video and graphic information formats included in the message. Your email address and the information included in your message may be used to respond to you, to address issues you identify, to improve this website, or to forward your
message to another ESF campus office for appropriate action. Your email address is not collected for commercial purposes and ESF is not authorized to sell or otherwise disclose your email address for commercial purposes. During your visit to esf.edu you may complete a transaction such as an online application. The information collected by ESF, including personal information volunteered by you in completing the transaction, may be used by ESF and may be disclosed by ESF for those purposes that may be reasonably ascertained from the nature and terms of the transaction in which the information was submitted. ESF does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age 13 or create profiles of children under the age 13. Users are cautioned, however, that the collection of personal information submitted in an email will be treated as though it was submitted by an adult, and may, unless exempted from access by federal or state law, be subject to public access. Disclosure of Information Collected Through This Website The collection of information through esf.edu and the disclosure of that information are subject to the provisions of the Internet Security and Privacy Act. ESF will only collect personal information through esf.edu or disclose personal information collected through esf.edu if the user has consented to the collection or disclosure of such personal information. The voluntary disclosure of personal information to ESF by the user constitutes consent to the collection and disclosure of the information by ESF for the purposes for which the user disclosed the information to ESF. However, ESF may collect or disclose personal information without consent if the collection or disclosure is: (1) necessary to perform the statutory duties of ESF, or necessary for ESF to operate a program authorized by law, or authorized by state or federal statute or regulation; (2) made pursuant to a court order or by law; (3) for the purpose of validating the identity of the user; or (4) of information to be used solely for statistical purposes that is in a form that cannot be used to identify any particular person. Further, the disclosure of information, including personal information, collected through esf.edu is subject to the provisions of the Freedom on Information Law and the Personal Privacy Protection Law. ESF may disclose personal information to federal or state law enforcement authorities to enforce its rights against unauthorized access or attempted unauthorized access to ESF's information technology assets. Retention of Information Collected Through this Website In general, the internet services log of ESF, comprising electronic files or automated logs created to monitor access and use of ESF services provided through esf.edu, is retained for 21 business days and then destroyed. Information concerning these records retention and disposition schedules may be obtained through the internet privacy policy contact listed in this policy. Access to and Correction of Personal Information Collected Through esf.edu Any user may submit a request to ESF's privacy compliance officer to determine whether personal information pertaining to that user has been collected and maintained through esf.edu. Any such request shall be made in writing and must be accompanied by reasonable proof of identity of the user. Reasonable proof of identity may include verification of a signature, inclusion of an identifier generally known only to the user, or similar appropriate identification. The address of the privacy compliance officer is: Vice President for Administration
Privacy Compliance Officer
SUNY College of Environmental Science and Forestry
1 Forestry Drive
Syracuse, New York 13210 The privacy compliance officer shall, within five (5) business days of the receipt of a proper request, provide access to the personal information if it exists; deny access in writing, explaining the reasons therefore; or acknowledge the receipt of the request in writing, stating the approximate date when the request will be granted or denied, which date shall not be more that 30 days from the date of the acknowledgment. In the event that ESF has collected personal information pertaining to a user through esf.edu and that information is to be provided to the user pursuant to the user's request, the privacy compliance officer shall inform the user of his or her right to request that the personal information be amended or corrected under the procedures set forth in section 95 of the Public Officers Law. Confidentiality and Integrity of Personal Information Collected Through esf.edu ESF is strongly committed to protecting personal information collected through esf.edu against unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Consequently, ESF limits employees access to personal information collected through esf.edu to only those employees' who need access to the information in the performance of their official duties. In addition, ESF has implemented procedures to safeguard the integrity of its information technology assets, including, but not limited to, authentication, authorization, monitoring, auditing and encryption. These security procedures have been integrated into the design, implementation and day-to-day operations of esf.edu as part of our continuing commitment to the security of electronic content as well as the electronic transmission of information. For website security purposes and to maintain the availability of esf.edu for all users, ESF employs software to monitor traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise damage esf.edu. Cookies Esf.edu uses cookies for stored login sessions and analytical purposes. When visiting esf.edu, ESF automatically collects and stores the following information about your visit:
The Internet Protocol address of the computer that accessed our website The type of browser, its version, and the operating system on which that browser is running The web page requested by the user The web page from which the user accessed the current web page The date and time of the user's request The pages that were visited and the amount of time spent at each page
None of the above-mentioned information is deemed to constitute Personal information by the Internet Security and Privacy Act. The information that is collected automatically is used to improve esf.edu's content and to help SUNY ESF understand how users are interacting with its website. This information is collected for statistical analysis and to determine what information is of most and least interest to our users. The information is not collected for commercial marketing purposes and SUNY ESF is not authorized to sell or otherwise disclose the information collected from esf.edu for commercial marketing purposes. This website uses Google Analytics and AdWords, a web analytics and advertising service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics and AdWords use "cookies," which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google. Information collected is subject to Google's privacy policies. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above. You may opt out of the AdWords cookie by visiting the Google advertising opt-out page or you may opt out of Google Analytics by visiting the Google Analytics opt-out page. Google has additional information available about its Remarketing Privacy Guidelines, and Restrictions. ESF also uses AdRoll and Facebook Pixel for digital marketing campaigns. Disclaimer The information provided in this privacy policy should not be constructed as giving business, legal or other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information provided through esf.edu. Contact Information For questions regarding this internet privacy policy, please contact our privacy officer via email at privacy@esf.edu or by regular mail at: Vice President for Administration
Privacy Officer
SUNY College of Environmental Science and Forestry
1 Forestry Drive
Syracuse, New York 13210 Definitions The following definitions apply to, and appear in italics, in this policy: Personal information: For purposes of this policy, "personal information" means any information concerning a natural person that, because of name, number, symbol, mark, or other identifier, can be used to identify that natural person. User: Shall have the meaning set forth in subdivision 8 of section 202 of the State Technology Law. 2/14/20
ESF Home Find People and Offices Site Index
Administration Links
Home
Administrative Updates
Board of Trustees
Digital Millennium Copyright Act
Institutional Effectiveness
Internal Control
SUNY Sexual Assault and Violence Response Resources (SAVR)
SUNY ESF Responsibilites for Reporting and Responding to Incidents of Sexual Harassment, Sexual Assault, or Sexual Violence
Title IX, Non-Discrimination Policy
Discrimination Complaint Procedure (DOC)
Nondiscrimination Policy
Title IX Policy and "Rules of Decorum" Addendum (PDF)
Office of Inclusion,
Accessibility — ESF is committed to providing accessible online materials. If you have issues, contact web@esf.edu for a prompt solution.
